Jeris Alan Jawahar

Address: 2510-204, Avent Ferry Road, Raleigh, NC 27606

E-Mail: jjawaha@ncsu.edu | alan.jeris@gmail.com

Phone: +1 (919) 917 0067 | GitHub: jerisalan | LinkedIn: jerisalan

Professional Summary

I am a passionate and budding programmer by profession with 2+ year's experience in data mining and visualization and web application development using Java and JavaScript coupled with quick learning and skilled problem solving ability.

Work Experience

NC State University

Raleigh, NC, USA

Graduate Research Assistant

Dec 2016 onwards

 Working on developing an automated planner for long term IoT service offerings in Smart Cities using dynamic Causal Inference and other differential equation models for Anticipatory Thinking.

Cerner Corporation

Bangalore, India

Software Engineer

July 2014-July 2016

- Prototyped and developed a robust web based scalable architecture to support data localization for MPages, an EHR. Was awarded the highest engineering award because of this.
- Developed an AI based recommender system (JavaScript frontend + Java backend) to support ICD-10 diagnosis concepts for determining appropriate billing fee by physicians for any patient visit.

Software Engineer Intern

Dec 2013-June 2014

 Developed an automated Test Driven Development Framework using QUnit and jQuery libraries for MPages Platform leading to incorporation of unit tests and facilitated writing quality code.

Blisslogix Technology Solutions Pvt Ltd

Chennai, India

Android Developer Intern

May 2012–June 2012

 Developed an Android app <u>Sify Gold and Silver Live</u>, which provides live gold prices, commodity market charts and tools to calculate gold and silver rates across the various Indian metros.

Technical Skills

- Programming Languages: JavaScript, Java (solid, day to day use); HTML/CSS, Oracle SQL, C++,
 C (Intermediate); R, Python, Node.js, MySQL (novice)
- Operating Systems: Experience with a wide range of Windows and UNIX environments.
- Miscellaneous: Android SDK, Eclipse IDE, Agile Methodology, React.js, Machine Learning

Education

North Carolina State University

Master of Science in Computer Science

Vellore Institute of Technology

Expected May 2018

GPA: 3.44/4

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science Engineering

June 2010-May 2014 GPA: 9.05/10

- Awarded merit-based undergraduate scholarship for excellence in academics
- o Member of National Social Service and volunteered in teaching under-privileged rural children.

Technical Projects

- News Categorization Led a team of 4 to develop Python application to automatically classify newsgroup content into respective types using MLP & SVMs and got accuracy between 85-90%.
- Droid Runner Developed an infinite running 2D Android game where the objective is to jump and collect things without falling to gain points.
- Diabetes Prediction Developed a supervised classification model for identifying main causes of diabetes and predicting whether a person is diabetic and achieved accuracies of 77.6%.
- R-Tree Programmed a Graphical User Interface (Java frontend) for spatial information querying to visualize "R-Trees - A Dynamic Index Structure for Spatial Searching" widely used in databases for indexing multi-dimensional information.

Awards and Recognitions

- o Won Cerner Masters, Cerner's highest engineering award among all global associates in Feb 2016.
- Awarded Chancellors Merit Scholarship offered to the top 3% of the cohort.

Research Publications

Amol Parikh, Nidhi Sharma and Jeris J Alan. Article: Modified Fast Bandwidth-Constrained Shortest
 Path Algorithm for MACO. International Journal of Computer Applications 69(23):41-44, May 2013